Hey, what's up?
I'm Tom.
I'm Zendaya.
I'm John.
I'm Sadie.
I'm Jacob.
And today, with the cast of Spider-Man: Brand New Day, we are taking GQ's Pop Quiz.
Round one, general comic trivia.
Oh, no.
What iconic line did Uncle Ben say to Peter Parker?
Oh, damn it!
See?
With great power comes great responsibility.
Boo!
Perfect.
Fair and square.
Next question, who created Spider-Man?
Oh, damn.
Oh, shit.
Stan Lee and Steve Ditko.
It's mine for Tom.
What supervillain does Ned Leeds become in the comics?
The Hobgoblin.
That's correct.
It's going to get harder, guys.
What did Mary Jane see Peter the first time...
Face it, Tiger.
You won?
I'm like...
Face it, Tiger.
I'm going to hold on.
If someone can pull the full sentence.
You hit the jackpot.
Face the tiger, you hit the jackpot.
There you go.
That's correct.
Point to Zendaya.
Really did.
All right.
Which issue of The Amazing Spider-Man did the Punisher first appear?
Oh, I don't know.
I actually don't know.
Which one?
Which issue of The Amazing Spider-Man did the Punisher first appear?
Over to you.
143.
129.
Wait.
That was good, though.
That was pretty close, man.
Yeah, that was pretty good.
Pretty close.
Last question in round one.
Who wrote the original comics run of Brand New Day?
Oh, damn.
We should all know this.
I know, embarrassing.
I'm sorry.
We love you.
The answer is...
Someone from Sony.
Oh, go on.
Dan Slott.
Sorry, shout out.
Shout out.
Shout out, Dan.
Round two.
This is MCU, sort of wider MCU multiverse knowledge.
Nice.
What high school did Peter, MJ, and Ned attend?
Midtown.
Full title?
Midtown High.
I'll accept it.
Midtown School of Science and Technology.
Science and Technology.
I'll accept it.
Question two.
What did Peter say to Doctor Strange after introducing himself in Avengers: Infinity War?
I don't know.
I say, oh, we're making our use of...
Oh, no.
No.
We're making our...
We're making our used up names.
We're using our made up names.
That's what I was trying to say.
Jumbling, bro.
I'm so tired.
We're making our used up names.
I just was helping.
Why do I keep...
We're using our made up names.
There you go.
I think I'm going to have to give this to Zendaya because you got her.
It's a half.
In Spider-Man: No Way Home, oh yeah.
What did Peter III, Andrew Garfield, think the Avengers were?
Tom.
A band.
That's correct.
You want to contribute, Jon, at some point?
I'm there.
He's coasting.
Yeah, I'm sending good vibes.
I'm sending good vibes.
What pizza place did Peter Parker work in the Sam Raimi Spider-Man 2?
It didn't even go off.
Joe's Pizza.
That is correct.
Jacob, you're on the board.
What villains did Peter Parker fight in The Amazing Spider-Man 2?
Oh, man.
Tom.
Rhino.
Electro.
Green Goblin.
And that's it, right?
That's it.
Yeah, that's it.
You got it.
That was great.
I really didn't know.
I'm going to write another one.
Yeah, right, right.
What was the name of Spider-Man's mecha in the Japanese television series?
He's like mecha-suit.
Mecha-droid.
Yeah, yeah.
Mecha-droid?
Leprechaun.
I would not have got that.
It was a weird show, guys.
It's a deep cut.
Yeah, that's a deep cut.
Round three, this is production knowledge.
Who filmed Tom Holland's audition video?
Let's go.
You know what?
I hit it first.
I'm going to let you have this, though.
Thank you.
You're so awesome.
Jonathan Edward Bernthal.
Hey, let's go.
Let's go.
Give it to John.
I got that last.
That's so pathetic.
What did Willem Dafoe wear on set to prevent his appearance in Spider-Man: No Way Home from being leaked?
I honestly forgot.
I think that was Zendaya.
That was you.
I'm a little more cloaked.
Who played Miles Morales' uncle in Spider-Man: Homecoming?
Oh, man.
Donald Glover.
That's correct.
Name both of Tom's stunt doubles.
Jacob.
Dave and Luke.
Yeah, that's technically correct.
That's technically correct.
That is technically correct.
And Greg.
Because there has been a bunch of stunt doubles.
And there's more.
And Chris.
Yeah, right.
Another one is from the other.
Movies as well.
But that is technically correct.
And we've had a lot.
But that's technically correct.
Give it to Jacob.
All right.
What two other Marvel projects has Spider-Man: Brand New Day director Destin Daniel Cretton directed?
Wonder Man and Shang-Chi.
That's correct.
That was kind of close.
It was close.
I don't know.
We're going to take that.
Michael?
Who got it first?
I'm gonna try it though.
I'm gonna try it.
What show had Spider-Man's first live action appearance?
Oh, damn.
It's that TV show, isn't it?
Yeah, on the right side.
He had his own TV show.
Yeah.
I just didn't like it.
It was called.
I just called The Amazing Spider-Man, right?
The Electric Company.
Oh, right.
The way that you replied was like, it was like really close.
It was a TV show.
No, right.
Yeah.
Okay, so this is finish the line.
So basically, I'm not going to tell you who said this, but if you can figure out what the second half of the line is, buzz in.
You know, I'm something of...
A scientist myself.
But he...
I didn't hit it fast enough.
Yeah, I think Tom got it.
That's my secret cap.
What?
That's your secret cap.
Did you say that?
I didn't say that.
No, you didn't say that.
No one here said that.
Something Tony Stark would say?
That's my secret cap.
But is it Spider-Man specific?
No.
I don't think so.
It's Spider-Man.
MCU.
It's someone that is in this movie said this.
Oh, it's Mark Ruffalo.
It's Mark Ruffalo, the Hulk.
He says, Tom, you get angry.
And he goes, that's my secret cap.
I'm always angry.
And then he goes, there you go.
That's correct.
It's points of Tom.
Here's another one.
One batch, two batch, Penny and dime, let go.
Damn, I would have never known.
That another point for John.
It crazy when that happens, isn't it?
Next line.
The power of the sun.
In the palm of my hand.
That's correct.
Otto Octavius.
Awesome.
Oh yeah, right when he's making like that thing.
If you're nothing without this suit.
Then you shouldn't have it.
That's right, till you start.
Bang!
Iron Man.
Alright.
Nice, well done.
I resent that.
Slander is spoken.
Oh.
Whoa.
Oh, shit.
Can we hear it again?
Absolutely.
I resent that.
Slander is spoken.
I don't know.
I'll give you a hint.
Another line this person typically says, like, I trust my barber.
What the fuck?
Give me pictures of Spider-Man.
Oh!
Oh, it's J. Jonah Jameson.
And the line is, in print, it's libel.
Spider-Man wasn't attacking the city.
He was trying to save it.
That's slander.
It is not.
I resent that.
Slander is spoken.
In print, it's libel.
You don't trust anybody.
That's your problem.
I trust my barber.
I would never have gotten that.
I'm trying to mess with you guys.
Yeah, I see.
Round five is, we're gonna have a draw Spider-Man competition.
Sadie, you gotta at least win this one, bro.
You gotta hit this one.
Sadie, I believe in you.
I'm gonna give you guys a minute.
Okay.
All right.
In three, two, one, go.
He's already gone.
I made a bad shape.
Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
I'm fucking this up.
Oh, it's going so sideways.
Sideways.
Yeah, I don't fuck this up.
Ten.
Nine.
Eight, seven, six, five, four, three, two, one.
All right, pencils down everybody.
I like the buildings.
Yeah, the building, actually the webs, like the spread out webs.
Yeah, it makes more sense.
A little abstract.
Jacob, let me see what you got.
Okay.
You definitely won.
Yeah, at least they might've killed it.
I think Sadie wins that.
Yeah, the web's stronger.
We just went with the belt.
Yeah, just the belt.
Just the belt.
You know, a simplified suit.
I was like, do you even wear a belt?
That's really good.
That's a really great one.
That's an actual symbol of the video game.
I like yours.
It's bad.
I started with this and then I saw Zendaya and I tried to get the eyes different.
The grin formation.
By vote, who do you think won?
Sadie.
Sadie?
For sure.
There was so much detail.
There's way more to it.
I was a window while Jacob breaks the set.
I'm Going to give state of the point by Democratic vote.
Yeah.
So guys, this is the rapid fire round.
Last round.
How many Spider-Man films are there?
Films starring Spider-Man?
Eight, nine, nine.
There's nine.
Oh, come on.
Technically, 14.
Damn.
There, like, you have to get other ones.
Yeah, not just, not just the live action one.
Yeah.
Who plays Spider 2099 in Into the Spider?
I don't know what his name is, the guy with the spikes.
He's like, no, he's like the big, like, who plays, like, who plays, or like plays, and who does the voice?
Who does the voice?
I'll give you a hint: he is in Star Wars and Dune and Inside Llewyn Davis.
He's a big guy.
Why am I all of a sudden...
my brain is not...
cannot function.
Help me.
Ask your Isaac.
Give him to Zendaya.
Where is Peter Parker from?
Queens.
Sadie, you were close, but sorry, Sadie.
Next question is: what was Peter Parker's first line in Captain America: Civil War?
Tom: fine.
Hey, May.
Fa, fa, fa.
Yes, you might.
Hey, May.
Then I say fine.
Then I say something like, "There's a crazy car parked outside," and then I see...
nice Peter Parker voice.
Thanks, Robert Downey Jr. Our next question is: what was the last thing Peter said to Tony Stark in Avengers: Infinity War?
Zendaya: "I don't want to go.
I don't want to go."
And then, "We've been through this."
Nope, it's not "I don't want to go."
Tom, buzz in.
I say, "I'm sorry."
Oh, perfect point for Tom.
He goes, like, you.
And this one's a toughie.
When is the first time, technically, that Spider-Man appeared alongside the X-Men in live action?
Wait, wait, sorry.
Technically.
When is the first time Spider-Man appeared in live action alongside the X-Men?
No idea.
Is it when he, like, went on to their set one time and he, like, and it was like a joke?
Was it?
Jacob, that is 100% correct.
Yeah, well, I remember watching this video because I was up late at night, and one of them was like a random fact about like 2002
movies.
No way.
And they were doing it at the same time, right?
They were like filming at the same time or something like that?
They were filming around the same time, yeah.
And then it's a Blu-ray DVD extra.
Yes.
Wait.
I am completely...
I'm so sorry.
Wow, I didn't think anyone was going to get that.
That was good.
All right, so.
I should win, though.
I mean, for that, I love.
The final score is Sadie with one point.
John, you have two points.
Jacob, you came in with four points.
Zendaya, you have a total of seven points.
And Tom, you win this pop quiz with a total of 10 points.
You are the winner of the GQ pop quiz.
Boo.
I've been playing this character for 10 years.
It's the pride of my life.
Seems like you guys have got to do a little bit more research before you grace the sets yet again.
Thank you.
I don't know.
I don't know about that, yeah.
I feel like we can run a few things back.
Yeah, for sure.
I could have gotten a couple more.